Woman's Club of Albany; Records mss139
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Membership, 1910-2009; 4; 2.4 cubic ft.
  - Early Membership Applications and Resignations, 1917-1927; 4.2
    - Early Resignations, E &F, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 37)
    - Early Resignations, G, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 38)
    - Early Resignations, H, I, &J, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 39)
    - Early Resignations, K &L, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 40)
    - Early Resignations, M, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 41)
    - Early Resignations, P &Q, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 42)
    - Early Resignations, R, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 43)
    - Early Resignations, S, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 44)
    - Early Resignations, T, U, &V, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 45)
    - Early Resignations, W, 1924-1927 (Box 3 (4-Membership), Folder 46)
  - Membership Files, 1910-2009; 4.3
    - New Membership Nominations, 1910 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 1)
    - Membership List Book, 1917-1918 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 2)
    - Membership List Book (1 of 2), 1919-1920 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 3)
    - Membership List Book (2 of 2), 1919-1920 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 4)
    - Resignations, ca.1920s (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 5)
    - Membership List Book ( 1 of 2), 1922 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 6)
    - Membership List Book ( 2 of 2), 1922 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 7)
    - Registration Cards, 1923 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 8)
    - List of Applications and Resignation, 1923 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 9)
    - List of Resignations, 1923 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 10)
    - New Member Lists, 1923-1924 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 11)
    - Invitation to vote and Election Ballot, 1923-1924 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 12)
    - New Members, 1924 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 13)
    - Membership List Book (1 of 2), 1924 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 14)
    - Membership List Book (2 of 2), 1924 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 15)
    - Paid Membership List, 1924-1925 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 16)
    - Typewritten Membership List, 1925 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 17)
    - Membership List Book (1 of 2), 1925-1926 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 18)
    - Membership List Book (2 of 2), 1925-1926 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 19)
    - Membership List Book (1 of 3), 1926-1927 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 20)
    - Membership List Book (2 of 3), 1926-1927 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 21)
    - Membership List Book (3 of 3), 1926-1927 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 22)
    - Membership List Book, 1927-1928 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 23)
    - Membership List Book, 1928-1929 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 24)
    - Membership List Pamphlet, 1933; 1936-1938 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 25)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1938 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 26)
    - Membership Applications, 1938 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 27)
    - Membership Applications, 1939 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 28)
    - Membership Applications, 1940 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 29)
    - Membership Applications, 1941 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 30)
    - Membership Applications, 1942 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 31)
    - Membership Applications, 1943 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 32)
    - Membership Applications, 1944 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 33)
    - Membership Applications, 1945 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 34)
    - Membership Applications, 1946 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 35)
    - Membership Applications, 1947 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 36)
    - Membership Applications, 1948 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 37)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1948; 1950 (Box 1 (4-Membership), Folder 38)
    - Membership Applications, 1949 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 1)
    - Membership Applications, 1950 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 2)
    - Membership Applications, 1951 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 3)
    - Membership Applications, 1952 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 4)
    - Membership Applications, 1953 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 5)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1953-1954 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 6)
    - Membership Applications and Resignations, 1954 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 7)
    - Membership List, 1954-1955 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 8)
    - Special Meeting of the Membership, 1955 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 9)
    - List of "Exes", 1955 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 10)
    - Membership Applications, 1955 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 11)
    - Membership Applications, 1956 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 12)
    - Membership List, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 13)
    - Membership Applications, 1957 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 14)
    - Membership List, 1957-1958 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 15)
    - Membership Applications, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 16)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 17)
    - New Member List, 1958-1959 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 18)
    - Membership List Pamphlets, 1958-1960 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 19)
    - Membership Applications, 1959 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 20)
    - Membership Totals, 1959-1960 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 21)
    - Membership Applications, 1960 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 22)
    - Blank Election Ballot and Tally of Votes, 1960 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 23)
    - Membership List Pamphlets, 1960-1962 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 24)
    - Election Ballot and Tally of Votes, 1961 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 25)
    - Membership Applications, 1961 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 26)
    - Resignations, 1961 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 27)
    - Blank Election Ballot, 1962 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 28)
    - Membership Applications, 1962 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 29)
    - Membership Applications, 1963 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 30)
    - Membership Applications, 1964 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 31)
    - Membership Applications, 1965 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 32)
    - Resignations, 1965-1971 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 33)
    - Membership Applications, 1966 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 34)
    - Membership Applications, 1967 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 35)
    - Membership Applications, 1968 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 36)
    - Election Results, 1968 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 37)
    - Membership Applications and Acceptance Letters, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 38)
    - Membership List Pamphlets, 1968-1971 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 39)
    - Election Ballot and Tally, 1970 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 40)
    - Membership Applications and Acceptance Letters, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 41)
    - Resignations, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 42)
    - New Members and Resigned Members Lists, 1971 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 43)
    - Membership Applications and Acceptance Letters, 1972-1976 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 44)
    - Resignations, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 45)
    - Resignations, 1976; 1979; 1980 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 46)
    - Club Inquiry and Survey, 1977 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 47)
    - Membership Applications, 1977-1979 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 48)
    - Club Inquiry and Survey, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 49)
    - List of Club Members, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 50)
    - List of Resignations and Deceased, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 51)
    - Membership List, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 52)
    - Resignations, 1984-1989; Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 53)
    - Membership List, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 54)
    - Membership List, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 55)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1987 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 56)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 57)
    - Blank Election Ballots, 1990 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 58)
    - Resignations, 1990-1996; 1998; 2002; 2004 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 59)
    - Club Member Incentives, ca. 1995 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 60)
    - Membership Applications, 1995 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 61)
    - Membership Roster, 1995-1996 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 62)
    - Membership Applications, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 63)
    - Membership Applications, 2001 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 64)
    - Membership Applications, 2004 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 65)
    - Membership Roster, 2006 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 66)
    - Membership Roster, 2008-2009 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 67)
    - Membership Renewal Applications, 2009 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 68)
    - Returning Members, 2009 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 69)
    - Blank Membership Applications (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 70)
    - Blank Membership Applications (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 71)
    - In Memoriam, Listing of Deceased Members Between 1911 and 1943, Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 72)
    - Membership Applications, Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 73)
    - Membership List, Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 74)
    - Resignations, Undated (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 75)
  - Resignations and Dropped Members Index Cards, 1914-1954; 4.4
    - Index cards, A-K, Predominantly Typed, 1914-1954 (Card-file 2)
    - Index cards, L-V, Predominantly Typed, 1914-1954 (Card-file 3)
    - Index cards, A-Z, Handwritten, 1914-1954 (Card-file 4)
  - Deceased Members Index Cards, 1914-1985; 4.5
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, A-B, 1914-1952 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 76)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, C-E, 1914-1962 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 77)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, F-H, 1912-1963 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 78)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, J-L, 1911-1985 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 79)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, M-O, 1914-1961 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 80)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, P-R, 1919-1957 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 81)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, S-T, 1911-1953 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 82)
    - Deceased Members Index Cards, V-Y, 1913-1953 (Box 2 (4-Membership), Folder 83)
- Scrapbooks, 1910-2007; 5; 5.07 cubic ft. 1
  This series contains scrapbooks and albums created by The Woman's Club of Albany. Books contain photographs, clippings, correspondence, newsletters, and other artifacts documenting events and activities at the Club. Initially members created a scrapbook every year.
  While this finding aid lists all the scrapbooks, not every scrapbook is available to be viewed by researchers. Early scrapbooks and a select number of later ones are very fragile and under review for possible conservation treatment. Those unavailable for review are noted as such.
  - Portraits of the Womens [sic] Club of Albany, Inc., 1910; 98.55 MB (Oversized 9)
    Currently unavailable to be reviewed because of present physical condition. Digital use copy.
  - Scrapbook, 1910-1911 (Oversized 10)
    Currently unavailable to be reviewed because of present physical condition.
  - Scrapbook, 1911-1912 (Oversized 11)
  - Scrapbook, Drama Department, 1911-1916 (Oversized 12)
  - Scrapbook, Children's Garden Committee, 1912-1916 (Oversized 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1912-1913 (Oversized 14)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1915 (Oversized 15)
  - Scrapbook, 1915-1916 (Oversized 16)
  - Scrapbook, 1916-1917 (Oversized 17)
  - Scrapbook, 1917-1918 (Oversized 18)
  - Scrapbook, 1918-1919 (Oversized 19)
  - Scrapbook, 1919-1920 (Oversized 20)
  - Scrapbook, 1920-1921 (Oversized 21)
  - Scrapbook, 1921-1922 (Oversized 22)
  - Scrapbook, 1922-1923 (Oversized 23)
  - Scrapbook, 1923-1924 (Oversized 24)
  - Scrapbook, 1924-1925 (Oversized 25)
  - Scrapbook, 1925-1926 (Oversized 26)
  - Scrapbook, 1926-1927 (Oversized 27)
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1928 (Oversized 28)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1929 (Oversized 29)
  - Scrapbook, 1929-1930 (Oversized 30)
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1931 (Oversized 31)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932 (Oversized 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Oversized 32)
  - Scrapbook, 1933-1935 (Oversized 33)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1936 (Oversized 33)
  - Scrapbook, 1936-1938 (Oversized 33)
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Oversized 34)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1941 (Oversized 35)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1942 (Oversized 36)
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Oversized 37)
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1949 (Oversized 38)
  - Scrapbook, 1949-1950 (Oversized 38)
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1951 (Oversized 39)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1958 (Oversized 40)
  - Scrapbook, 1957-1958 (Oversized 38)
  - Scrapbook, 1958-1962 (Oversized 41)
  - Scrapbook, Juniors of Albany, 1959-1960 (Oversized 42)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1962 (Oversized 43)
  - Scrapbook, Juniors of Albany, 1964-1966 (Oversized 44)
  - Scrapbook, 1964-1972 (Oversized 45)
  - Scrapbook, 1983-1987 (Oversized 46)
  - Scrapbook, 1997-2007 (Oversized 47)
- Events and Programs, 1912-2010; 6; 1.07 cubic ft.
  Materials from events and programs hosted by the WCA are included in this series. The majority of the flyers and advertisements for WCA events are from the twenty first century, with one or two from the 1970s and 1990s. This series also contains event calendars from the 1940s, which were most likely sent out to WCA members monthly. The only evidence of earlier events is from playbooks, dramatic journals, and songbooks retained by the Club. These plays were likely purchased by the WCA for a fee to the playwright, and the women performed these one act plays every few months at an event hosted by the Dramatic Department. Event calendars can also be seen in the Monthly News, found in the Publications series.
  - Ticket to Club Performance of Mice and Men, 1912 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 1)
  - The Dramatist Journal Retained by WCA, 1915-1916 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Plays Retained by the Club, 1916; 1932; 1937-1938 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Report on Club Activities, 1921-1925 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Formation Day Celebration Program, ca. 1926 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
  - Resume of Club Activities, 1926-1930 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Event Calendars, 1926 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Art Exhibit, 1927 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Event Calendars, 1927 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Songbooks Retained by the Club, 1927 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Event Calendars, 1928 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Resume of Club Activities, 1931-1935 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Event Calendars, 1934 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 12)
  - 25th Anniversary Celebration Program, 1935 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Event Calendars, 1935 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Event Calendars, 1936 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Event Calendars, 1937 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Event Calendars, 1938 (Box 1 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1939-1942 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Plays Retained by the Club, 1940 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Plays Retained by the Club, 1942 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Dramatic Department Performance Programs, 1942 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Event Calendars, 1942 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Event Calendars, 1943 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Event Calendars, 1944 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Plays Retained by the Club, 1944 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Christmas Program, 1948 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Event Calendars, 1948-1949 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Invitation to Club's 45th Anniversary Celebration, 1955 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Planning for Founder's Day Celebration, 1955 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Hospitality Tea Invitation Tally, 1959 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 13)
  - 50th Anniversary Celebration Program, 1960 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Art Department Exhibit List, 1962 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Guest Logbook for an Event, 1966 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Woman's Club Art Show at Colonie Center Mall Correspondence and Paperwork, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Informational Packet about the CTM School of Singing and Speech Hosted at Woman's Club, 1978 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 18)
  - President's Message with Event Calendar, 1978 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Dinner Party Program, 1979 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Calendar of Events, 1985 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Calendar of Events, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Calendar of Events, 1987 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Tickets to Various Events Hosted by the Club, 1988; 1993-1994; Undated (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 24)
  - List of Card Party Door Prizes Contributors and Generic Letter Sent to Businesses Asking for Gifts, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Event Agenda, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 26)
  - Preview of the Importance of Being Earnest, 1996 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 27)
  - Dinner at the Culinary Institute of America, 1996 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 28)
  - Summer Hat Show and Luncheon, 1997 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 29)
  - Luncheon and Fashion Show, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 30)
  - Open House Flyers, 1997 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 31)
  - A Summer Celebration, 1997 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 32)
  - Program Schedule, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 33)
  - Third Annual Antique Appraisal, 2001 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 34)
  - Semi-Annual Garage Sale, 2001 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 35)
  - Annual Open House, 2004 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 36)
  - Good Book and Good Food for Good Works, 2005 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 37)
  - Rummage Sale, ca. 2005 (Box 2 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 38)
  - Good Book and Good Food for Good Works, 2006 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Through a Woman's Eyes, 2006 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 2)
  - 3rd Annual Foster Children's Holiday Party, 2006 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Program Ideas, 2006-2007 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Antiques Show and Sale, 2007 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Masquerade Extravaganza, ca. 2007 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Festival of Trees Financials, Planning, and Programs, 2008 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Springtime Arts and Crafts Show, 2008 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Children's Book Drive, 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 9)
  - 5th Anniversary of Renaissance Celebration, 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 10)
  - 6th Annual Holiday House Tour, 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Program Ideas, ca. 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Teas and Trees Event Proposal, 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 13)
  - WCA Sponsored Drives, 2009 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 14)
  - A Moveable Feast Sponsored by WCA, 2010 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 15)
  - BBQ at the Barn, 2010 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Centennial Celebration-Teas to Tastings, 2010 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 17)
  - 3rd Annual Springtime Craft Show, ca. 2010 (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Antique Road Show, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Play Scripts Performed by the Club, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Victorian Scavenger Hunt, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Member Involvement Event Log, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Program for A Midsummer Night's Dream Performance, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Events Hosted by the Club, Undated (Box 3 (6-Events and Programs), Folder 24)
  - World's Greatest Event Planner Medal, Undated (Card-file 5)
- Publications, 1911-2007; 7; 1.91 cubic ft.
  The Publications series includes all materials the Womans Club of Albany published throughout its history. Publication of WCA news transitions in the following pattern: Annual Announcements, 1911-1930; Monthly News, 1930 Oct.-1942; The Messenger, monthly magazine, 1944-1951 May; The Messenger, monthly newsletter on legal size paper, 1951 Oct.-early-1960s; The Messenger, monthly newsletter on letter-sized paper, 1970-1973, 1979-1980.
  Although the publication format changed, the information disseminated to members remained unchanged. There is always a message from the President and a calendar of events, followed by reports from all the departments. The constitution and directory of officers and committees are often included as well. In the October 1930 Monthly News, there is a message from the WCA President that talks about the transition from yearly news to monthly. She states that the Board of Directors decided to give monthly announcements a year-long trial, because it believe that this would be a more convenient and accurate method of keeping members informed. At the end of the message from the President, member input is solicited, favorable or otherwise. It is assumed that the new news layout received positive feedback, as the WCA published news monthly for the next twelve years, until 1942. There are no monthly news pamphlets from 1943 found in this collection, so it is unknown whether there were any published during that year. In 1944 the WCA began publishing The Messenger. The Messenger was a magazine the WCA published every month except for June, July, and August. The first editorial explains that the magazine is a WCA project that was started by Mrs. William Arnstein, who was the advertising manager. The WCA published its news in The Messenger for the next three decades, but the layout changed. In October 1951 The Messenger transitioned from a magazine to a newsletter printed on legal-sized paper. The farewell issue of the magazine informs members about the upcoming changes, but gives no direct reason for it. In the mid-1960s The Messenger varied between a small booklet-like format and a legal-sized newsletter. From 1970-1973 the WCA printed The Messenger on letter-sized paper. The only other issues are from 1979/1980 and these are also printed on letter-sized paper. It is unknown how the WCA published news in the intervening years and afterwards.
  Also included in the Publications series are house rental pamphlets, WCA informational pamphlets, and programs. The house rental pamphlets give a brief history of the Clubhouse as well as pricing information and payment policies. An information pamphlet published in 2007 was aimed at attracting new members. It gives information pertaining to the WCA as well as the costs and benefits of being a member.
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1911-1912; 1912-1913 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1913-1914; 1914-1915 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1914-1915; 1915-1916 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1916-1917 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1917-1918; 1918-1919 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1918-1919; 1919-1920 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1919-1920 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1920-1921 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 8)